In Vietnam, the wind doesn't blow. It sucks.
Full Metal Jacket is a drama, war film directed by Stanley Kubrick.
A pragmatic U.S.
Marine observes the dehumanizing effects the U.S.-Vietnam War has on his fellow recruits
from their brutal boot camp training to the bloody street fighting in Hue.
Pvt. Joker, played by Matthew Modine.
Animal Mother, played by Adam Baldwin.
Pvt. Pyle, played by Vincent D'Onofrio.
Gny. Sgt. Hartman, played by R. Lee Ermey.
Eightball, played by Dorian Harewood.
Rafterman, played by Kevyn Major Howard.
Full Metal Jacket is a 1987 war film directed and produced by Stanley Kubrick
from a screenplay he co-wrote with Michael Herr and Gustav Hasford.
The film is based on Hasford's 1979 autobiographical novel The Short-Timers.
It stars Matthew Modine, R.
Lee Ermey, Vincent D'Onofrio, Adam Baldwin, Dorian Harewood, and Arliss Howard.
The storyline follows a platoon of U.S.
Marines through their boot camp training at Marine Corps
Recruit Depot Parris Island, South Carolina.
The first half of the film focuses primarily on privates J.
Davis and Leonard Lawrence, nicknamed "Joker" and "Pyle" respectively, who
struggle under their abusive drill instructor, Gunnery Sergeant Hartman.
The second half portrays the experiences of Joker and other Marines in the Vietnamese
cities of Da Nang and Huế during the Tet Offensive of the Vietnam War.
The film's title refers to the full metal jacket
bullet used by military servicemen.
Full Metal Jacket was theatrically released in the United States on June 26, 1987,
by Warner Bros., and in the United Kingdom on September 11, 1987.
It was the last of Kubrick's films to be released during his lifetime.
The film grossed $120 million against a budget of
$16.5–30 million and was widely acclaimed.
It was nominated for an Academy Award for Best Adapted Screenplay, and was also nominated for two BAFTA Awards, while
Ermey was nominated for a Golden Globe Award for Best Supporting Actor – Motion Picture for his performance.
In 2001, the American Film Institute placed the film at number 95
in its poll titled "AFI's 100 Years...100 Thrills."
The film explores themes of rescue, sniper, vietnam war, suicide, vietnam.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.